<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" generated="2015-08-04T09:54:41">
<Characters>
<ID>1</ID>
<Character>Al Borland</Character>
<Description>The lovable, good-natured co-host of Tool Time whose work with his hands has won him a place in people&apos;s hearts; a sensitive, amiable man in stark contrast to the stereotypical male of touch masculinity and proud chauvinism. At times, Al struggles to keep a steady woman relationship and his lifestyles and manners make him an unpopular, dull creature among others. Nonetheless, with his caring, innocent nature, the humble Al has proven America to be the everyman, the nice guy who finishes last, the underdog.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Home Improvement, sitcom</Source>
<LinkImage>AlBorland.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>2</ID>
<Character>Al Bundy</Character>
<Description>The popular shoe salesman who made America laugh because of a lackluster life he led after high school; a hapless man who never got what he wanted which was to play football. Instead, he works fo a minimum-wage job that he hates to provide for a family that disrespects him. When able to reverse his dreadful, downtrodden situation, he never seems to win, or make it happpen or come out on top. So while the aging, relic endures a dissatisfying existence he gives comfort to ever average, low-paid American who almost won the big one.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Married with Children, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>I fight honking traffic just for the privilege of putting cheap shoes onto the cloven hooves of people like you. I&apos;ll never play football like I wanted to. I&apos;ll never know the touch of a beautiful woman. And I&apos;ll never know the joy of driving through the city without a bag over my head. But I&apos;m not a loser. Because, despite it all, me and every other guy who&apos;ll never be what they wanted to be, is out there, being what we don&apos;t want to be, forty hours a week, for life. And the fact that I haven&apos;t put a gun in my mouth, you pudding of a woman, makes me a winner!</Quote>
<LinkImage>AlBundy.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>3</ID>
<Character>Alyosha</Character>
<Description>The stable-minded, loving novice in a Russian monastery, Alyosha finds close mentorship with the monastic elder, Zosima, and love from feuding school boys. Caught in a clashing family struggle over finances and lust, Alyosha contines his honest, religious, caring ways -leading by example. With murder dripping its blood, jealousy treading its steps, the young religious cadet carries the love of Christ with him. This little known young man turned a family name of madness and violence completely around for kindness and humanity, testimony that meekness is a powerful trait.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Brothers Karamazov, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>Alyosha.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>4</ID>
<Character>Arthur Dimmesdale</Character>
<Description>The New England minister with sad, weary eyes and a steady hand over his heart. Pained by a sinful act, Arthur Dimmesdale walks the earth sick and scared of a lost reputation and redemptive God. He lacks the courage to reveal himself. Through profound liturgies and lessons he feels the hard weight of a Puritan society. As his accomplice in crime carries her shame openly, Reverend Dimmesdale tortures his red mark in secret. But open to human eyes, Arthur finally gushes out what was so long kept dormant underneath. His boulder of pain kept him the meek lamb he so long preached about.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Scarlet Letter, novel</Source>
<Quote>I, whom you behold in these black garments of the priesthood,—I, who ascend the sacred desk, and turn my pale face heavenward, taking upon myself to hold communion, in your behalf, with the Most High Omniscience,—I, in whose daily life you discern the sanctity of Enoch,—I, whose footsteps, as you suppose, leave a gleam along my earthly track, whereby the pilgrims that shall come after me may be guided to the regions of the blest,—I, who have laid the hand of baptism upon your children,—I, who have breathed the parting prayer over your dying friends, to whom the Amen sounded faintly from a world which they had quitted,—I, your pastor, whom you so reverence and trust, am utterly a pollution and a lie!</Quote>
<LinkImage>ArthurDimmesdale.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>5</ID>
<Character>Athlete Dying Young</Character>
<Description>The smart lad who dodged and hurdled the vanity of the world. No laurels to crown, no records to beat, this athletic specimen cut early down in life is better for it. His soul will now feed on eternal salvation away from the Barmecidal feast and crowds, cheers, trophies, and tokens. We find it a sad sight for young talent to diminish. We hurt to see a town&apos;s beacon to be stunted and uprooted in its blossoming. But we learn of the brief garland, the withering laurel, the fading name, but also meek souls who flourish far from earthly fame and fortune.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>A.E. Housman poem</Source>
<Quote>Smart lad, to slip betimes away/From fields where glory does not stay,/And early though the laurel grows/It withers quicker than the rose./Eyes the shady night has shut/Cannot see the record cut/And silence sounds no worse than cheers/After earth has stopped the ears:/Now you will not swell the rout/Of lads that wore their honours out,/Runners whom renown outran/And the name died before the man</Quote>
<LinkImage>AthleteDying.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>6</ID>
<Character>Barney Gumble</Character>
<Description>The middle-aged town drunk who lives a loveless, aimless life on a bar stool. For whatever reason, Barney&apos;s childhoold promise dissolved away into a bottle. We see the antics and the jokes. We hear the dull voice and long burps. But we imbibe a lonely, soulful creature who would like a sober way out. As addiction mounts through the years, as Springfield passes along its events, as times progresses, Barney, somebody&apos;s best friend, a bar owner&apos;s steady customer, will be sure to keep his rightful post. But that doesn&apos;t mean the end of the dreaming, of the hoping; and we admit he had not yet died.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>The Simpsons, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>My name is Barney Gumble. I&apos;m forty, I&apos;m single, and I drink. There&apos;s a line in Othello about a drinker: &apos;Now a sensible man, by and by a fool, and presently a beast.&apos; That pretty well covers it. Don&apos;t cry for me, I&apos;m already dead.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Barney.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>7</ID>
<Character>Bartleby</Character>
<Description>The stoic, mysterious clerk of a Wall Street law office who lives and dies alone. Familyless, friendless, Bartleby lives as a frozen sentinel through his existence. When commanded by a boss, beseeched by co-workers, urged by strangers, Bartleby gives the usual refrain: &quot;I prefer not to.&quot; Eventually, he is fired; eventually, he is homeless; eventually, he starves to death. No one knows the how or why. But this unknown scrivener evokes some trait of humanity, some element of suffering and endurance. And we pause to take in his message in the silence of our hearts.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>Herman Melville short story</Source>
<Quote>He remained as ever, a fixture in my chamber. Nay—if that were possible—he became still more of a fixture than before. What was to be done? He would do nothing in the office: why should he stay there? In plain fact, he had now become a millstone to me, not only useless as a necklace, but afflictive to bear. Yet I was sorry for him. I speak less than truth when I say that, on his own account, he occasioned me uneasiness. If he would but have named a single relative or friend, I would instantly have written, and urged their taking the poor fellow away to some convenient retreat. But he seemed alone, absolutely alone in the universe. A bit of wreck in the mid Atlantic.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Bartleby.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>8</ID>
<Character>Belle</Character>
<Description>The sympathetic maiden who tamed a ruthless beast. From modest origins in a small town, Belle sacrificed herself for a father&apos;s welfare. Caught in an enchanted castle with intolerant, vigilante townspeople, Belle fights for virtue. For anyone who thinks outer beauty is not the manifestation of inner beauty, behold this lovely, gentle being. An avid reader, an outspoken young woman with ideas, Belle shines light on a dark kingdom, casting off spells, turning gargoyles into angels, and a beast into a human. She even shows the story of love can be new and vibrant and not a tale as old as time.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Beauty and the Beast, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>Belle.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>9</ID>
<Character>Bernard</Character>
<Description>The bookish nerd of a friend who showed how responsibility and diligence in his schoolwork can lead to success years later. Bernard was liked but not well liked in high school. He suffered the burdens of false values where men are judged by reputation and popularity among peers, while others, himself included, fall by the wayside as nobodys. Yet, the poor hardwarking Bernard endured his unpopularity and the cruel mockery for his anemic, worrisome personality. Eventually, this small iota of a man rose up in status and significance from a dissed, weak kid to an important lawyer arguing a case to the Supreme Court. In the end, his childhood nightmare woke up to the American Dream. </Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>Death of a Salesman, play</Source>
<LinkImage>Bernard.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>10</ID>
<Character>Bigger Thomas</Character>
<Description>A restless, uneducated twenty-year old black male whose life&apos;s story was being in the wrong place at the wrong time. Crawling out from the lower rung of the social ladder in the cramped constriction of Chicago&apos;s South Side, poor Bigger Thomas has been limited all his life by the white man in all thinking, feeling, and doing. Never the hard-core animal prevalent in most ruthless serial killers or hopeless, indifferent man who has nothing to lose, Bigger only wanted was denied him: life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness. Instead, he was doomed to a six-by-four prison cell and an electric chair.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Native Son, novel</Source>
<Quote>Mr. Max, I sort of saw myself after that night. And I sort of saw other people, too. Well, it&apos;s sort of funny, Mr. Max. I ain&apos;t trying to dodge what&apos;s coming to me. I know I&apos;m going to get it. I&apos;m going to die. Well, that&apos;s all right now. But really I never wanted to hurt nobody. That&apos;s the truth, Mr. Max. I hurt folks &apos;cause I felt I had to; that&apos;s all. They was crowding me too close; they wouldn&apos;t give me no room. Lots of times I tried to forget &apos;em, but I couldn&apos;t. They wouldn&apos;t let me. Mr. Max, I didn&apos;t mean to do what I did. I was trying to do something else. But it seems I never could. I was always wanting something and I was feeling that nobody would let me have it. So I fought &apos;em. I thought they was hard and I acted hard. But I ain&apos;t hard, Mr. Max. I ain&apos;t hard even a little bit.</Quote>
<LinkImage>BiggerThomas.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>11</ID>
<Character>Billy Pilgrim</Character>
<Description>A weak boy soldier who in later years meets an alien race that opens up to him the truth of measured time. Back and forth Billy relives the nonlinear progression of his life, seeing his family members&apos;, his acquaintances&apos;, and his own death countless times. He even witnesses the purple realm of Death itself and no longer fears it. With a sensitive heart bleeding at sights of a starved war horse, homeless bums on rail cars, a phone operator on the opposite end, Billy continues on or so it goes. Yet he teaches us all to live life in moments and not timelines events in chronology.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Slaughterhouse Five, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>BillyPilgrim.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>12</ID>
<Character>Bleeding Gums Murphy</Character>
<Description>The middle-aged saxophonist who mentors a talented, young protégé, but sadly carries the weight of the world on his shoulders. Poor, hapless Bleeding Gums Murphy once a highly successful recording artist, now suffers the pangs of depleted funds and lost stardom. Now, the jazzman roams alleys, streets, and bridges attempting to bring out of dark nights the living entity of art and music. Sadly, the soul-torn musician passes away dying like he lived: unremembered and unloved. Yet ultimately, Bleeding Gums shows us all the painful beauty of transforming life&apos;s woes into tender lyrics and heartfelt notes that last beyond lifetimes; and how the blues is the crying anthem of the meek.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>The Simpsons, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>Oh, I&apos;m so lonely,/Since my baby left me./I got no money,/And nothing is free./Oh, I been so lonely,/Since the day I was born./All I got is this rusty,/This rusty old horn.</Quote>
<LinkImage>BleedingGums.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>13</ID>
<Character>Bob Cratchit</Character>
<Description>An always self-denying, faithful servant especially in face of heartless authority, Bob Cratchit works as a low-paid clerk treated poorly at his job. But in spite of his misery, he continues to show loyalty to his boss and his endearing family. Pushed by a business-hungry, capitalistic system and a poverty-stricken English slum, poor Mr. Cratchit must struggle in past, present, and future. Yet, the warmth of his loving wife and children make the journey easier and worthwhile. Always patient even driven under the lash by the slave driver, he reminds us all the true humbleness and purity of the human spirit.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>A Christmas Carol, novella</Source>
<LinkImage>BobCratchit.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>14</ID>
<Character>Brooks Hatlen</Character>
<Description>An old crook who found peace within the menacing walls of Shawshank prison; the warm-hearted prison librarian doomed because of a cold-blooded past becomes a caretaker of a broken-winged bird. So when Brooks is finally paroled, the scared, sad old man is unable to survive on the outside. Cars fly by in a dizzying speed. A store manager adds to annoying stress. A halfway house proves to be a poor home for a fearful old scoundrel. So poor hapless Brooks misses his old life of lines and wardens, and struggles to make it each day in society, learning that redemption and retribution usually lasts a lifetime and beyond.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>The Shawshank Redemption, movie</Source>
<Quote>The parole board got me into this halfway house called &quot;The Brewer&quot; and a job bagging groceries at the Foodway. It&apos;s hard work and I try to keep up, but my hands hurt most of the time. I don&apos;t think the store manager likes me very much. Sometimes after work, I go to the park and feed the birds. I keep thinking Jake might just show up and say hello, but he never does. I hope wherever he is, he&apos;s doin&apos; okay and makin&apos; new friends. I have trouble sleepin&apos; at night. I have bad dreams like I&apos;m falling. I wake up scared. Sometimes it takes me a while to remember where I am. Maybe I should get me a gun and rob the Foodway so they&apos;d send me home. I could shoot the manager while I was at it, sort of like a bonus. I guess I&apos;m too old for that sort of nonsense any more. I don&apos;t like it here. I&apos;m tired of being afraid all the time. I&apos;ve decided not to stay. I doubt they&apos;ll kick up any fuss. Not for an old crook like me.</Quote>
<LinkImage>BrooksHatlen.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>15</ID>
<Character>C. Green</Character>
<Description>The unidentified, anonymous man who jumped out of the twelfth floor of a Brooklyn hotel room. Just an assumed name -C. Green- was plastered on a nine-line newspaper print of this thirty-five year old suicidal. No one knew who he was, why he did it, or what he wanted or needed if they even cared except that his senseless death paralleled his meaningless life. Poor, hapless C. Green who was no unique standout in life, just a duplicated face in the crowd, just another number in the masses, Now, the fateful creature lies as an exploded body on a concrete pavement with blood and brain fragments nearby. His rebellion came with shock. Yet, a hollow surface existence ended in deep, profound impact for everyone.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>Thomas Wolfe short story</Source>
<Quote>Or when, with strong faces turning towards the setting sun, hawk-eyed and Indian-visaged men bore gun-stocks on the western trails and sternly heard the fierce war-whoops around the Painted Buttes--where, then, was Green? Was never there with Drake&apos;s men in the evening when the sails stood in from the Americas! Was never there beneath the Spaniard&apos;s swarthy eye at Vincent&apos;s Cape! Was never there in the red-oak thicket in the morning! Was never there to hear the war-cries round the Painted Buttes! No, no. He was no voyager of unknown seas, no pioneer of western trails. He was life&apos;s little man, life&apos;s nameless cypher, life&apos;s man-swarm atom, life&apos;s American--and now he lies disjected and exploded on a street in Brooklyn!</Quote>
<LinkImage>Cgreen.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>16</ID>
<Character>C-3PO</Character>
<Description>The worry-prone, protocol droid who was built and programmed amid the crossfire of a raging star wars. Trained in over six million forms of communication, Threepio brings an air of genteelism and decorum, lost among the dry sands of barren planets. Scared of spaceships, he conquers the feat for a team. He translates. He explains. He helps along the way. As a dark Empire descends, Threepio is destroyed but then is salvaged back together. Though really a robot, a heap of scrap and metal with wires protruding, C-3PO carries human qualities of frailty, concern, and thoughtfulness, holding up a mirror to our better selves.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Star Wars, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>C3PO.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>17</ID>
<Character>Captain Ahab</Character>
<Description>The maniacally driven sea captain on a relentless chase for a white whale. After losing a leg the lonely whaleman with boiling blood and smoking brow launches a forty-year campaign of revenge. Through his hot pursuit of the leviathan, Ahab broods on life&apos;s themes in painful eloquence. Deep under the madness though, Ahab exhibits love of a wife and child, and friendship with a noble, first mate. Symbolizing America&apos;s pursuit of riches and power, mankind&apos;s battle over nature, good versus evil, poor Ahab piles all rages and hungers in the hump of his prey and dives to his lonely death to destroy it. </Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Moby Dick, novel</Source>
<Quote>Glorious ship! must ye then perish, and without me? Am I cut off from the last fond pride of meanest shipwrecked captains? Oh, lonely death on lonely life! Oh, now I feel my topmost greatness lies in my topmost grief. Ho, ho! from all your furthest bounds, pour ye now in, ye bold billows of my whole foregone life, and top this one piled comber of my death! Towards thee I roll, thou all-destroying but unconquering whale; to the last I grapple with thee; from hell&apos;s heart I stab at thee; for hate&apos;s sake I spit my last breath at thee. Sink all coffins and all hearses to one common pool! and since neither can be mine, let me then tow to pieces, while still chasing thee, though tied to thee, thou damned whale!</Quote>
<LinkImage>CaptainAhab.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>18</ID>
<Character>Captain Willard</Character>
<Description>A reserved war veteran who couldn&apos;t make it on the outside of a Vietcong jungle. Miserable in a peaceful life, Captain Willard took a mission into a jungle war zone. Facing bombs, noise, missiles, grenades, flying bullets, and relentless heat, Captain Willard and his crew of misfits continues on into the horror, the horror. Maybe just an errand boy sent by grocery clerks to collect a bill, he performs his task. But before and after, he bears witness to barbarism, foreign culture, human madness, and pitiful war. Coming out with a full-bred, pulsating heart and intact senses, Captain Willard shows he is not a hollow man.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Apocalypse Now, movie</Source>
<Quote>&quot;Someday this war&apos;s gonna end.&quot; That&apos;d be just fine with the boys on the boat. They weren&apos;t looking for anything more than a way home. Trouble is, I&apos;d been back there, and I knew that it just didn&apos;t exist anymore.</Quote>
<LinkImage>CaptainWillard.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>19</ID>
<Character>Carlton Banks</Character>
<Description>The preppy, pedantic straight-A student who got everything materially but not socially. Bred from an upper class life, poor Carlton never quite settled in social circles; never quite felt the continual fond embrace of a girl; never quite belonged to the close network of cliques. Somewhat snobby, Carlton neverthless symbolizes the sad penalty of success; how even the good and honest never win in the late 20th century America. However, Carlton whose taste in popular culture usually are at odds with his peers, always exhibits a vivacious spirit that remains eternally aflame despite being denied social belonging.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Fresh Prince of Bel-Air, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>You think I&apos;m a sellout... Why? Because I live in a big house where I dress a certain way? Or maybe it&apos;s because I like Barry Manilow?...Being black isn&apos;t what I&apos;m trying to be, it&apos;s what I am. I&apos;m running the same race and jumping the same hurdles as you, so why are you tripping me up? You said we need to stick together, but you don&apos;t even know what that means. If you ask me, you&apos;re the real sellout.</Quote>
<LinkImage>CarltonBanks.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>20</ID>
<Character>Cash Bundren</Character>
<Description>The reticient carpenter who is always willing to give especially in danger. As a troubled family prepares to journey to bury a mother, Cash hardly evokes an emotion or utters a word except through swings to carve out a wooden coffin. On and on he grinds, pounds, and fashions his wood pieces. His family members have come to talk to the background to the axe&apos;s grinds. Even in the midst of danger, with a leg nearly broken, cement hardening over the limb, the courageous carpenter, wordless to the end, gives his last breath. But his wooden pieces and beloved tools live on.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>As I Lay Dying, novel</Source>
<Quote>How do our lives ravel out into the no-wind, no-sound, the weary gestures wearily recapitulant: echoes of old compulsions with no-hand on no-strings: in sunset we fall into furious attitudes, dead gestures of dolls. Cash broke his leg and now the sawdust is running out. He is bleeding to death is Cash.</Quote>
<LinkImage>CashBundren.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>21</ID>
<Character>Charles Foster Kane</Character>
<Description>The classic story of rags to riches of a poor boy from Colorado who rose to become an eminent New York newspaper magnat. Charles Foster Kane continued to garner wealth, prestige, honor, and power. But he learns the sad toll paid on the road to success. Wife to second wife, an attempt at politics, a palace estate in Florida, Charles lived the American Dream. But loneliness trickled in; the cutthroat business asked for more; the empire falls. Despite it all, as Charles loses all possessions and prestige, he carries the boyhood sunshine of his youth, symbolized in a wooden sled that can never burn away.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Citizen Kane, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>CharlesKane.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>22</ID>
<Character>Charley Parks</Character>
<Description>Caught in a confused world peopled by misguided beings in a misunderstood universe, poor, lonely Charley wanders atray through his daily routine. His only hope, only faint whisper of life, enough to overcome his drab existence is a miniature figure in a museum doll house. There, the socially awkward, mentally anguished, emotionally distraught Charley falls in love with a wooden lady piece. Away from a sister and mother, too blind to his heartrending tragedy and too deaf to hear the mute cry of his soul, Charley with a pure, innocent essence helps turn imagination into reality, alienation into companionship, survival into love.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Twilight Zone, tv show</Source>
<Quote>They tried to tell me you weren&apos;t real. They tried to make me think you were only something I imagined. Of course I knew better. But I pretended to believe them. Because if I hadn&apos;t done that, I would still be in the hospital and I would never have seen you again. That would have been terrible because you see, I love you…Dr. Wallman said it happened because I needed a simple world that I could undersand. But your world isn&apos;t simple. Is it? No world with people in it is. There&apos;s always loneliness, suffering and heartache. Look at you, crying because you&apos;re alone. Well, I&apos;ve been alone all my life. Oh people tried; my mother, my sister, they tried very heard to understand. But they can&apos;t. You could. We could understand each other and help each other and love each other.</Quote>
<LinkImage>CharleyParks.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>23</ID>
<Character>Charlie Bucket</Character>
<Description>The poor boy who won the golden ticket. Hard-luck in family affairs, Charlie&apos;s story starts off as the good kid who finishes last. But hope comes in a chocolate candy bar. Accompanied by peevish, snotty kids, Charlie travels through a magical, fanciful factory of innumerable treats. He learns the lessons along the way and his good deed shines in a weary world. From a story whose sure end was defeat, Charlie shows us that the little guy can win; and that the good guy with purity in his soul who suddenly got everything he ever wanted can live happily ever after. </Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Willy Wonka and the Chocolate Factory, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>CharlieBucket.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>24</ID>
<Character>Charlie Gordon</Character>
<Description>The poor, metally retarded janitor and delivery boy at the local bakery who is taken advantage of by the outside world; a simple-minded, childlike innocent thirty-two year old man crippled emotionally and socially by a disability. And yet Charlie undergoes an experiment that heightens his I.Q. to genius status, he learns the sad reality of the world. Because of a scientist treating him as a lab rat, an unrequited love with a former teacher, and a troubled familial past, the once, pure, childlike soul transforms into a cynical, arrogant, even suicidal being. And yet we all learn from Charlie that being human and pure in spirit carries wtih it no I.Q.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Flowers for Algernon, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>CharlieGordon.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>25</ID>
<Character>Clarisse McClellan</Character>
<Description>The beautiful soul wrapped in a seventeen-year old girl who with a curious consciousness and love of people and nature is an outcast in the future. Clarisse discovered what most never do: the meaning of life. Against a dehumanizing, speedy, totalitarian society, Clarisse longs for early sunrises and morning dew, waving away the long, stretched billboards and speed-hungry passers-by who see brown streaks as cows and green streaks as grass. Poor, darling Clarisse, a most odd being in a futuristic landscape, suffers an untimely end. Why? Because her only crime was being tired of fact-learning in schools; for slowing down the pace just to walk and talk; and for being an individual thinker in a stifling, conforming universe. Yes, Clarisse we wish to go in the abyss with you than continue on in this robotic herd of an existence.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Fahrenheit 451, novel</Source>
<Quote>Have you ever watched the jet cars racing on the boulevards down that way. I sometimes think drivers don’t know what grass is, or flowers, because they never see them slowly. If you showed a driver a green blur, Oh yes! he’d say, that’s grass! A pink blur! That’s a rose garden! White blurs are houses. Brown blurs are cows. My uncle drove slowly on a highway once. He drove at forty miles an hour and they jailed him for two days. Isn&apos;t that funny, and sad, too? I rarely watch the &apos;parlor walls&apos; or go to the races or Fun Parks. So I&apos;ve lots of time for crazy thoughts, I guess...Bet I know something else you don&apos;t. There&apos;s dew on the grass in the morning. And if you look there&apos;s a man in the moon. My uncle was arrested another time -did I tell you? For being a pedestrian. Oh, we&apos;re most peculiar</Quote>
<LinkImage>ClarisseMcClellan.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>26</ID>
<Character>Daredevil</Character>
<Description>The blind superhero and criminal defense attorney who stands up for the law and justice in the streets and in the courtroom. With a tragic past in Hell&apos;s Kitchen, New York, Daredevil the man without fear began as the lost and lonely boy without sight. Taken in and trained by a mentor, slowly a superhero was developed. Able to see with a radar sight among heightened other senses, the Daredevil fights crime and stands up for the little man even with vengeful eyes toward a kingpin. From helpless to hero, we see that meekness symbolizes greatness; and we trust it better that justice in all forms is blind.</Description>
<SourceType>tv animated series</SourceType>
<Source>Spiderman, tv animated series</Source>
<Quote>I couldn&apos;t deal with the shame of what I seen my dad doing. It was the last thing I ever saw. The stuff from the truck was radioactive waste and it was against the law to transport it through the city. But somebody didn&apos;t care about the law, or about broken lives, or about the value of life at home... My blindness seemed to enhance all my other senses: smell, touch, taste. Now I could see better than before. It was kind of a natural radar but it was so new it confused me. Then, I met a mysterious man named Stick. I wish the world could know about all the effort, all the long hours, where Stick took a lost and lonely blind kid and taught me to see in ways I never knew existed...He helped me to live up to the nickname when kids would tease me when they thought I was blind and helpless -the Daredevil. Now, I am confident, fearless, and am close, so close, to confronting my greatest enemy. He&apos;ll pay for what he&apos;s done to the innocent, to the helpless, to my father.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Daredevil.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>27</ID>
<Character>Data</Character>
<Description>The eternal student of human nature who at the same time explores countless star systems makes his own frontier into mankind&apos;s foibles and follies. A sentient, artifical lifeform known as an android, Data has longed for human emotion depsite being an outsider of society. Nonetheless, his honest and innocent curiosity has mirrored the intrinsic goodness of flesh and blood beings. Thus, Data experiences friendship with fellow crewmembers, romantic sentiments with few partners, and kinship with an android daughter. In the end, his impressive computational skills fall short compared to his demonstration of the beauty of being human. </Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Star Trek: The Next Generation, tv show</Source>
<LinkImage>Data.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>28</ID>
<Character>Denver</Character>
<Description>The neglected girl tragically facing the trials of slavery. For eighteen long, lonesome years, Denver lived in isolation, dragged around by a socially outlawed mother. For eighteen years, Denver never knew a friend or brother, as they ran away from home. For eighteen years, she continued on through terrible distances. Though haunted by a home, a ghost, Denver beat the odds. She advanced her schooling and headed towards college. Through all the heinous crimes of humanity -slavery, murder- this poor, ragged black girl emerges as a forgotten but nonetheless noteworthy heroine.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Beloved, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>Denver.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>29</ID>
<Character>Dorothy</Character>
<Description>The sweet, dear girl from a small town in Kansas who dreams of something else over the rainbow beyond her rural home. As a tornado crashes through, Dorothy finds herself in a magical, imaginative world and even befriends meek characters with a lack of something. So she tries to find home down the yellow brick road toward the Emerald City. Through it all, from wicked witches to wizards, Dorothy learns home is where the heart is and not much exists beyond the backyard of human company; and that no one lacks -they&apos;re just not aware.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Wizard of Oz, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>DorothyGale.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>30</ID>
<Character>Edmund Tyrone</Character>
<Description>The youngest of a toubled family with the most potential. Caught in a melee of alcohol, tuberclosis, sick mother, agitated father, jealous brother, Edmund finds himself a lost relic, adrift, wandering throughout life. Never wanted or wanting, he nonetheless exhibits worth in literature and philosophy. As a seaman he imbibes the intense rhythm and pulsating energy of wind and waves, losing identity and time but finding meaning at last! But the fog returns and Edmund is battling a family again, human affairs again; the same tragic tale of young intellectuals surviving day to day.</Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>Long Day&apos;s Journey into Night, play</Source>
<Quote>When I was on the Squarehead square rigger, bound for Buenos Aires. Full moon in the Trades. The old hooker driving fourteen knots. I lay on the bowsprit, facing astern, with the water foaming into spume under me, the masts with every sail white in the moonlight, towering high above me. I became drunk with teh beauty and singing rhythm of it, and for a moment I lost myself -actually lost my life. I was set free! I dissolved into the sea, became white sails and flying spray, becamse beauty and rhythm, became moonlight and the ship and the high dim-starred sky! I belonged, without past or future, within peace and unity and a wild joy, within something greater than myself or the life of Man, to Life itself!</Quote>
<LinkImage>EdmundTyrone.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>31</ID>
<Character>Edna Pontellier</Character>
<Description>The poor pawn in a patriarchical society, stifled, controlled, and limited by conservatism that somehow always seeped through the cracks and crevices of nineteen-century American life. Twenty-eight year old Edna, wearied and alone by the automaton existence of dutiful wife and mother, finds solace in newly awakened feelings. Finally given new life away from the pale, dead sigh as a New Orleans mistress, the idealistic, independent Enda emotionally lingers on piano strains and sexual urges. She disregarded society&apos;s conventions to resuscitate a soul. She swims out to capture limitless seas. She paints away a gray voided life.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Awakening, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>EdnaPontellier.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>32</ID>
<Character>Elizabeth Bates</Character>
<Description>The soul-torn creature spit on and trampled on by a distant, drunk husband and the coal mining life. More a mother than a wife, a numbed being than a sentient soul, poor Elizabeth must endure for the sake of a household with inhuman stamina. The unlucky wife of a coal miner whose only marriage duty was to wait: wait in exasperation, wait in fear, wait in hatried, wait by candlelight for her husband&apos;s nightly drunken raids. Then, hapless Elizabeth plagued by the mocking perfume of chrysanthemums finally learns of her husband&apos;s death, relieving her of a heavy weight but not its aftermaths.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>D.H. Lawrence short story</Source>
<LinkImage>ElizabethBates.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>33</ID>
<Character>Emily Grierson</Character>
<Description>A once, elite noblewoman of a myopic Southern town soon becomes a secluded hermit in a two-story house. After an important father died so did the once young, vibrant creature with only a finger count of acquaintances to stir the sameness across the years. And all the while a gossiping town that never forgives or forgets keeps humming the same, sad refrain: &quot;poor Emily, poor Emily.&quot; Indeed it was for poor, hapless Emily who watches the years pile on, growing sick with time, old with iron-gray hair, fat with inactive isolation; stripped of all rank, class, and status in a sad, earthly condition: not, barely surviving, doubtfully existing. So when it was time for Emily to be carried off after the bygone of generations, the china-painter becomes a bride to death itself.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>William Faulkner short story</Source>
<LinkImage>EmilyGrierson.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>34</ID>
<Character>Emily Webb</Character>
<Description>The innocent, young darling of Grover&apos;s Corner, New Hampshire who found in a lonely cemetery on top of a hill, the passing, unenjoyed transience of human life. Poor Emily, bred from an automaton family, reared by romantic love, sadly died in untimely childbirth. From there, the sensitive creature with heart pouring with nostalgia and sadness discovers the unappreciated hours on earth and how human beings seldom relish each moment while it lasts. Once a school girl, a financee, a wife, now among the dead; once from an unknown town at the turn of the century, now a spirit who learns the eternal, universal truths humans will always fail to know.</Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>Our Town, play</Source>
<Quote>I can&apos;t. I can&apos;t go on. It goes so fast. We don&apos;t have time to look at one another. I didn&apos;t realize. All that was going on in life and we never noticed. Take me back - up the hill -  to my grave. But first: Wait! One more look. Good-by, Good-by, world. Good-by, Grover&apos;s Corners? Mama and Papa. Good-bye to clocks ticking? And Mama&apos;s sunflowers. And food and coffee. And new-ironed dresses and hot baths? And sleeping and waking up. Oh, earth, you&apos;re too wonderful for anybody to realize you.</Quote>
<LinkImage>EmilyWebb.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>35</ID>
<Character>Emmeline Grangerford</Character>
<Description>Deep in a big, old-fashioned double log house, a precious gem once dwelled inside; a sensitive daughter whose swaddling clothes at birth was a funeral crape and veil. The yound Emmelinealways wrote poetry, tender heartfelt lays and tributes to any recently deceased living form. Always she lived in a world surrounded by obituaries, accidents, and patient suffering. Even more, Emmeline created painfully beautiful paintings of soul-torn subjects until she became a subject herself. Yet no one wrote her any poetry or made her a drawing. But no doubt the ominous, all-powerful Death for a little while loomed as a pathetic figure alongside this compassionate soul.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>Emmeline.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>36</ID>
<Character>Forrest Gump</Character>
<Description>The simple-minded young man who got every succesful thing to go his way and still epitomizes humility and humbleness. Growing up, poor Forrest always endured the stigmatized harshness of being mentally challenged. Yet from a war veteran to a ping pong celebrity to a shrimp tycoon to a world status marathoner, Forrest&apos;s life has been the microcosm of the American saga. A honest, modest hero and innocent spirit who only wanted love from a tender mother, a stubborn lieutenant, and especially a childhood sweetheart. In the end, he made us taste the sweetness of life&apos;s delicious and at times unknown chocolate.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Forrest Gump, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>ForrestGump.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>37</ID>
<Character>Frankenstein monster</Character>
<Description>A horrible-looking progeny of a maddened, ambitious scientist who embodies the very spirit of benevolence and love. Deformed in an ugly appearance on a juggernaut frame, the monster, nameless and unloved, sets his foot on a world he seldom understands. But finding a restful hoaven in a dark hovel away froms scornful, prejudiced men, the creature learns the beauty of all humanity from simple cottagers. Nevertheless, after an unsuccessful reception the once innocent being turns into a tortured soul reeking destruction and death. So on the poor, soul-torn creature trudges through rugged terrain, reminding us all the shameful behavior of mankind to judge others with their eyes.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Frankenstein, novel</Source>
<Quote>I am an unfortunate and deserted creature; I look around, and I have no relation or friend upon earth. These amiable people to whom I go have never seen me, and know little of me. I am full of fears; for if I fail there, I am an outcast in the world for ever…They are kind -they are the most excellent creatures in the world; but, unfortunately, they are prejudiced against me. I have good dispositions; my life has been hitherto harmless, and in some degree beneficial; but a fatal prejudice clouds their eyes, and where they ought to see a feeling and kind friend, they behold a detestable monster.</Quote>
<LinkImage>FrankensteinMonster.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>38</ID>
<Character>Fredo Corleone</Character>
<Description>Fumbling at the most inopportune times, Fredo is last in line in the Corleone family -even being ousted by a kid brother. Fighting for respect, Fredo always loses. Yet he stays dutiful in the family business. But inadequacies torment him as his helpless father dies on a curb next to him. Given peripheral enterprises to run, Fredo manages but in the scheming and politics he crosses the line. Then, a wife mockes him openly, feeding fire to his self-pity. At last a quiet lake on a dusky fishing scene, his sad life ends. Yet a family still talks of him, proving one can die but not perish.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>The Godfather, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>FredoCorleone.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>39</ID>
<Character>Gart Williams</Character>
<Description>An ad agency exec caught in the a push-push-push business where he msut rush-rush-rush through life. Everyday poor Gart Williams is forced to compete in an inhuman existence for profit and speed. Then, an unsympathetic wife adds to the overwhelming burden for her sensitive, soul-torn husband. At last, grabbing a few moments of respite, hapless Gart finds serentiy and solace in a dream-contrived place called Willoughby. After exasperating days and a lifetime of stress and ulcers, Gart years for this peaceful, summertime 19th century paradise. Sadly such a haven is out of reach, leaving Gart to ask the untimely question: will it be?</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Twilight Zone, tv show</Source>
<Quote>I would prefer, though never asked before, a job, any job at all where I could be myself. Where I wouldn’t have to climb on a stage and go through a masquerade every morning at nine o’clock. And mouth all the dialogue and play the executive and make believe I’m the bright young man who’s on his way up ‘cause I’m not that person, Janey. You’ve tried to make me that person but that isn’t me. That isn’t me at all...I know where I&apos;d like to be...Willoughby. It was summer, very warm. Kids were barefooted. One of them had a fishing pole. It all looked like a Currier and Ives painting. Bandstand, bicycles, wagons. I&apos;ve never seen such serenity. It was the way people must have lived a hundred years ago. Crazy dream.</Quote>
<LinkImage>GartWilliams.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>40</ID>
<Character>Gerty MacDowell</Character>
<Description>The sorrow-faced, Irish dame lovely who shows us on a balmy, summer even the surreal capacity of tenderness and love. A solitude young lady caught up in a marriage no more than its title and name finds her very dream of love dressed in black. With a soul moved to embrace pain adn stand up as companion through Earth&apos;s dark matter, Gerty, who too knows the burden of a nameless sadness, gives to us a pair of sentimental eyes, a lame gait, and jilted but tender spirit. And presents to us at last how beauty itself can climb down from its high pedestal and walk among the peopled earth as a foreigner and comforter.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Ulysses, novel</Source>
<Quote>He was in deep mourning, she could see that, and the story of a haunting sorrow was written on his face. She would have given worlds to know what it was...The very heart of the girlwoman went out to him, her dreamhusband, because she knew on the instant it was him. If he had suffered, more sinned against than sinning, or even, even, if he had been himself a sinner, a wicked man, she cared not. Even if he was a protestant or methodist she could convert him easily if he truly loved her. There were wounds that wanted healing with heartbalm. She was a womanly woman not like other flighty girls, unfeminine, he had known, those cyclists showing off what they hadn&apos;t got and she just yearned to know all, to forgive all if she could make him fall in love with her, make him forget the memory of the past. Then mayhap he would embrace her gently, like a real man, crushing her soft body to him, and love her, his ownest girlie, for herself alone.</Quote>
<LinkImage>GertyMacDowell.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>41</ID>
<Character>Girl, Monsieur Verdoux</Character>
<Description>The lonely young woman caught in the rain on a night street. Thought to be a worthless derelict, a perfect specimen for a newly concocted poison, the girl proves otherwise. With a hard-luck story of a three-month jail sentence, for petty larceny, an invalid husband recently deceased, and current destitution, meekness held the form of a brunette wrapped in a raincoat. When cynicism should be her only outlet, she reminds us the beauties of life: spring mornings, summer nights, music, art, love, and the little kindness that makes a sad, blundering world beautiful again. </Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Monsieur Verdoux, movie</Source>
<Quote>Yet life is wonderful. Everything. Spring morning, summer night, music, art, love...[Love is] giving, sacrificing, the same a mother feels for a child...[My husband] was wounded in the war, a hopeless invalid. That&apos;s why I loved him. He needed me, depended on me, he was like a child. But he was more than a child to me; he was a religion, my very breath. I would have killed for him. No, love is something very real and deep…I don&apos;t know why I&apos;m carrying on like this. I was beginning to lose faith in everything and this happens and you want to believe all over again…it&apos;s a blundering world, and a very sad one; yet a little kindness can it beautiful.</Quote>
<LinkImage>GirlMonsieurVerdoux.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>42</ID>
<Character>H.E.R.</Character>
<Description>The personified symbol of a music movement, of a subculture for disenfranchised youth, of a righteous resistance to mainstream norms. Nevertheless, H.E.R. becomes tainted by gangster and thug personalities. From a proud beacon of Afrocentricity to a ghetto-fabulous thing-piece commercialized for mass appeal, we see a beautiful, black heroine fallen by the wayside and shrunk to a defiled creature. Oh, the two decade dissolution of something hopeful! Oh, the art disintegrated to the bare facts of life! Oh, the beauty, rhythm, social consciousness never realized!</Description>
<SourceType>song</SourceType>
<Source>Common rap song</Source>
<LinkImage>HER.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>43</ID>
<Character>Hamlet</Character>
<Description>Torn between avenging a murdered father, reconciling an unfaithful mother and impious girlfriend, the young intellectual prince of Denmark meets his tragedy. Hamlet, clothed entirely in black, lingers in black thoughts, with a black future of seiges and death. Continuously in meditative monologues, the vacillating prince struggles with his decision. He sees clearly the futility of it all, the emptiness that all flesh returns to. So all the time, Hamlet longs for the eternal sleep where at the last is answered: to be or not to be?</Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>Hamlet, play</Source>
<Quote>To be, or not to be: that is the question:/Whether &apos;tis nobler in the mind to suffer/The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune,/Or to take arms against a sea of troubles,/And by opposing end them? To die: to sleep;/No more; and by a sleep to say we end/The heart-ache and the thousand natural shocks/That flesh is heir to, &apos;tis a consummation/Devoutly to be wish&apos;d. To die, to sleep;/To sleep: perchance to dream: ay, there&apos;s the rub;/For in that sleep of death what dreams may come/When we have shuffled off this mortal coil,/Must give us pause: there&apos;s the respect/That makes calamity of so long life;/For who would bear the whips and scorns of time,/The oppressor&apos;s wrong, the proud man&apos;s contumely,/The pangs of despised love, the law&apos;s delay,/The insolence of office and the spurns/hat patient merit of the unworthy takes,/When he himself might his quietus make/With a bare bodkin? who would fardels bear,/To grunt and sweat under a weary life,/But that the dread of something after death/The undiscover&apos;d country 
from whose bourn No traveller returns, puzzles the will/And makes us rather bear those ills we have/Than fly to others that we know not of?/Thus conscience does make cowards of us all</Quote>
<LinkImage>Hamlet.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>44</ID>
<Character>Hannah</Character>
<Description>The tenacious, flower growing out of the smoky muddiness of a Jewish ghetto; a noble, brave woman who tried hard to fight a corrupt and cruel system. Poor Hannah who grew up scrubbing kitchen floors and tending laundry still has a lovely soul to dream pure, honest aspirations. For all she wanted was a chance to a live in an uncertain future on a green countryside with a chicken farm with growing grapes and apples. Yet iron heels too quickly stomped on this war-torn daffodil whose sweet tears have shown the world the awful, sour chapter in human history. Nonetheless, her frank spirit shines like a beloved star too far for foul mankind to ever reach. </Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>The Great Dictator, movie</Source>
<Quote>Hannah, can you hear me? Wherever you are, look up Hannah! The clouds are lifting! The sun is breaking through! We are coming out of the darkness into the light! We are coming into a new world; a kindlier world, where men will rise above their hate, their greed, and brutality. Look up, Hannah! The soul of man has been given wings and at last he is beginning to fly. He is flying into the rainbow! Into the light of hope, into the future! The glorious future, that belongs to you, to me and to all of us. Look up, Hannah. Look up!</Quote>
<LinkImage>Hannah.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>45</ID>
<Character>Henry Corwin</Character>
<Description>Far from the jolly optimism of St. Nick, poor Henry Corwin, a purposeless relic, works as a deaprtment story Santa Clause. Sadly the Yuletide festivities force Henry to find solace in a bottle since the miserable, alcoholic drunk must witness day in and day out the drab, dirty hopelessness of poverty all around him and people who forget the charity and purity of Christmas. He must with an aching heart look upon destitute children whose only Christmas presents are unrequited hopes. Nonetheless, Henry lands upon a mysterious bag which gives each poor slum child their heart&apos;s desires. So a compassionate soul who felt helpess to shabby conditions becaomes a great, grand gift giver to the meek.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Twilight Zone, tv show</Source>
<Quote>I don&apos;t know how to tell you Mr. Dundee. I don&apos;t know at all. All I know is that I&apos;m an aging, purposeless relic of another time and I live in a dirty rooming house on a street filled with hungry kids and shabby people where the only thing that comes down the chimney on Christmas Eve is more poverty! You know another reason why I drink Mr. Dundee? So that when I walk down the tenements I can really think it is the North Pole and the children are elves and I&apos;m really Santa Claus bringing them a bag of wondrous gifts for all of them! I just wish Mr. Dundee just one Christmas….Only ONE….that I could see some of the hopeless 
ones, and the dreamless ones, just on one Christmas, I&apos;d like to see the meek inherit the Earth, and that is why I drink Mr. Dundee and that is why I weep.</Quote>
<LinkImage>HenryCorwin.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>46</ID>
<Character>Hester Prynne</Character>
<Description>One misbegotten mistake, one shameful sin and a vivacious, lovely young woman is lowered into a pale and drab existence. Never smiles or sunshine to welcome her, just a scaffold&apos;s shadow and somber sadness to walk beside her. Poor, hapless Hester survives rather than lives from day to day during the religious, stern epoch of Puritan close-mindedness. Despite her situation, she gives to others as alms to the poor and nurse to the sick -never wanting reward or acknowledgement. So on through the burden of years, the gray adorned ghost of a woman, alienated life as a social outcast, an ex-husband casting revenge, a possessed daughter reeking havoc, the embrodierer continues on. We shudder to think she will carry a joyless soul and earthly woe to a dark grave.  </Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Scarlet Letter, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>HesterPrynne.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>47</ID>
<Character>Holden Caufield</Character>
<Description>The seventeen-year old dropout from Pencey Prep who becomes the voice of teenage America; the soul-torn young man caught in the world of hypocrisy and superficiality. Sadly, Holden is unreachable by teachers, psychiatrists, or others alike for his gloomy, misanthropic, and cynical nature that forces him into alienation. His sensitivity and intelligence makes him distrustful of the adult world. Only does the playful laughter of children, in their innocent and genuine ways, intrigue his heart and fancy. We can scarcely imagine this depressed youth can still dream especially a pure one of protecting children in fields of rye and from falling off a cliff.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Catcher in the Rye, novel</Source>
<Quote>Anyway, I keep picturing all these little kids playing some game in this big field of rye and all. Thousands of little kids, and nobody&apos;s around - nobody big, I mean - except me. And I&apos;m standing on the edge of some crazy cliff. What I have to do, I have to catch everybody if they start to go over the cliff - I mean if they&apos;re running and they don&apos;t look where they&apos;re going I have to come out from somewhere and catch them. That&apos;s all I do all day. I&apos;d just be the catcher in the rye and all. I know it&apos;s crazy, but that&apos;s the only thing I&apos;d really like to be.</Quote>
<LinkImage>HoldenCaufield.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>48</ID>
<Character>Humboldt</Character>
<Description>The insomniac, manic depressive poet who lived and died like all American poets are supposed to: a brief moment in the sun and squalid, secluded years to follow. Humboldt carried within him all the creative energy, intellectualism, and passion that a human being could contain in one skull. After one great publication, he continued in the career of letters but struggled through relationships, finances, friendships. From Chicagoland to the New York area, Humboldt tried with academic seats, political aims, screenplays, and with raising art to a higher level above crass commercialism. But he died a nobody yet succeeded in the one effort all poets aim for: inspiration.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Humboldt&apos;s Gift, novel</Source>
<Quote>The Times was much stirred by Humboldt&apos;s death and gave him a double-column spread. The photograph was large. For after all Humboldt did what poets in crass America are supposed to do. He chased ruin and death even harder than he had chased women. He blew his talent and his health and reached home, the grave in a dusty slide. He plowed himself under. Okay. So did Edgar Allan Poe, picked out of the Baltimore gutter. And Hart Crane over the side of a ship. And Jarrell falling in front of a car. And poor John Berryman jumping from a bridge. For some reason this awfulness is peculiarly appreciated by business and technological America. The country is proud of its dead poets. It takes terrific satisfaction in the poets&apos; testimony that the USA is too tough, too big, too much, too rugged, that American reality is overpowering. And to be a poet is a school thing, a skirt thing, a church thing.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Humboldt.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>49</ID>
<Character>J. Alfred Prufrock</Character>
<Description>The quintessential modern man sweltering in the stifled existence of urban living. Filled with insecurities of personality and appearance, Prufrock ruminates over his sad, middle-aged indecisions. He tries hard to dare the universe in consummating a romantic relationship but he admits that he&apos;s no Prince Hamlet, no prophet, and here is no great matter. Educated and alone, Prufrock looks out at the scene of things, never being a part of it. Through cityscapes of drains and smoky haze, measuring his life in coffeespoons, Prufrock shows us the modern, 20th century Western individual as an isolated, lost figure in human history.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>T.S. Eliot poem</Source>
<Quote>And indeed there will be time/To wonder, “Do I dare?” and, “Do I dare?”/Time to turn back and descend the stair,/With a bald spot in the middle of my hair—/[They will say: “How his hair is growing thin!”]/My morning coat, my collar mounting firmly to the chin,/My necktie rich and modest, but asserted by a simple pin—/[They will say: “But how his arms and legs are thin!”]/Do I dare/Disturb the universe?/In a minute there is time/For decisions and revisions which a minute will reverse./For I have known them all already, known them all:—/Have known the evenings, mornings, afternoons,/I have measured out my life with coffee spoons;/I know the voices dying with a dying fall/Beneath the music from a farther room./So how should I presume?</Quote>
<LinkImage>JAlfredPrufrock.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>50</ID>
<Character>James Evans</Character>
<Description>Everyday he is busting and scratching for food on the table, a roof over head, opportunities for his three children. But everyday, the 1970s Chicago South Side gives no helping hand as the working class father must work two grueling jobs just to get the bare crumbs called hope. Mired in a recession, walled in by poverty, the proud James epitomizes the strong, black man. Sometimes a hopeful job or chance comes along only to prove impossible or inconvenient. But still he continues surviving the only way he knows how: somehow, someway.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Good Times, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>A job? What the hell good is a job? Man, I got a job. I got two jobs. Hell, I had jobs all my life. I want something more for my son. I want him to have an opportunity and you and I both know opportunities only come through with an education.</Quote>
<LinkImage>JamesEvans.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>51</ID>
<Character>Jay Gatsby</Character>
<Description>The Long Island millionaire who hosts lavish weekly parties in his luxurious home but never partook in the festivities. From meager origins, Jay Gatsby shunned poverty and hungered for wealth even if it meant bootlegging and securities fraud. Jay, a creature of his time, got caught in the rapture of the brimming 20s and the bustling New York. He even gets lovestruck along the way for an old flame. Blinded by it all, Jay Gatsby faces accidents adn death but deep down he was just a lost boy looking for respect and love. His near empty funeral reveals the Great Gatsby is just a meek Gatsby.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Great Gatsby, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>JayGatsby.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>52</ID>
<Character>Jerry Renault</Character>
<Description>The grade school cadet who stands up for all the picked on kids of school bullies, near and far. Jerry holds steadfast in a private school filled with intimidating figures from peer to teacher. Going against the tide, daring the universe, hanging onto his principles, Jerry refuses to sell chocolates. So the torment intensifies. Brawls erupt as he tastes blood and broken teeth, as fists rain down its fury on him. A David against a Goliath, courage gains a face and heart with this young man. Jerry even teaches a close friend that they can beat him up but can&apos;t beat him.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Chocolate War, novel</Source>
<Quote>Just now, Janza was beating me up. But he wasn&apos;t winning. I mean, you can get beat up and still not lose. You can look like a loser but don&apos;t have to be one. Janza&apos;s the loser, Goober. He&apos;ll be a loser all his life. He beat me up but he couldn&apos;t beat me. They want you to fight, Goober. And you can really lose only if you fight them. That&apos;s what the goons want. And guys like Archie Costello. You have to outlast them, that&apos;s all.</Quote>
<LinkImage>JerryRenault.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>53</ID>
<Character>Jim Casey</Character>
<Description>The ex-preacher who took to the road with a family toward California. Jim made a few graces over meals, a few prayers over the dead but his heart was no longer in the established faith. Out of the church now, the wandering middle-aged man roams the abandoned countryside in search of a calling. Alone, sad, lost Jim finds his purpose among the people. Hot in human strife, he is arrested by the police but after enlisting in a worthy cause. Still believing the holy spirit is the human spirit and that all people are part of one big soul, Jim finds everyday things holy.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Grapes of Wrath, novel</Source>
<Quote>I&apos;ll go anyways. Somepin&apos;s happening. I went up an&apos; I looked, an&apos; the houses is all empty, an&apos; the lan&apos; is empty, an&apos; this whole country is empty. I can&apos;t stay here no more. I got to go where the folks is goin&apos;. I&apos;ll work in the fiel&apos;s, an&apos; maybe I&apos;ll be happy...I ain&apos;t gonna preach...I ain&apos;t gonna baptize. I&apos;m gonna work in the fiel&apos;s, in the green fiel&apos;s, an I&apos;m gonna be near to folks. I ain&apos; gonna try to teach &apos;em nothin&apos;. I&apos;m gonna try to learn. Gonna learn why the folks walks in the grass, gonna hear &apos;em talk, gonna hear &apos;em sing. Gonna listen to kids eatin&apos; mush. Gonna hear husban&apos; an&apos; wife a-pounding the mattress in the night. Gonna eat with &apos;em and learn. Gonna lay in the grass, open an&apos; honest with anybody that&apos;ll have me. Gonna cuss and an&apos; swear an&apos; hear the poetry of folks talkin&apos;. All that&apos;s holy, all that&apos;s what I didn&apos; understan&apos;. All them things is the good things...I wonder what they is for a fella so lonely.</Quote>
<LinkImage>JimCasey.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>54</ID>
<Character>Jim of Huck Finn</Character>
<Description>The humble slave that escapes his rough servitude with a young boy. Away on a wigwam and raft, Jim and his companion become entangled with the worst characters the world has to offer. But through a caring heart, bleeding with homesickness for his family, the Negro runaway slave finds his way to freedom. Always a practical as well as superstitious man, the self-denying Jim welcomes in open arms a young friend who crosses the color barrier, the shackle&apos;s long chain, and the vigilante mob&apos;s fast pursuit during America&apos;s darkest, merciless chapters.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Adventure of Huckleberry Finn, novel</Source>
<Quote>Pooty soon I’ll be a-shout’n for joy, en I’ll say, it’s all on accounts o’ Huck; I’s a free man, en I couldn’t ever ben free ef it hadn’t ben for Huck; Huck done it. Jim won’t ever forgit you, Huck; you’s de bes’ fren’ Jim’s ever had; en you’s de only fren’ ole Jim’s got now. Dah you goes, de ole true Huck; de on’y white genlman dat ever kep’ his promise to ole Jim.</Quote>
<LinkImage>JimHuckFinn.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>55</ID>
<Character>Joan Clayton</Character>
<Description>The young African American restauranteur who enjoys the highs and lows of upscale, urban LA living. Formerly a lawyer caught in a dead-end fix, Joan decided to take a detour on a one-way street toward her dreams. Sadly, poor Joan on the relentless search for Mr. Right goes from one relationship to another throughout the years. Burdening herself with too many demands, she finds herself cornered and not growing. Fortunately, she finds strength among three vivacious lady friends. But Joan can never entirely open her soul to a beloved companion. So the sad prospect of a lone spinster clouds her tearful eyes date after date.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Girlfriends, sitcom</Source>
<LinkImage>JoanClayton.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>56</ID>
<Character>Job</Character>
<Description>Where before rigidly-endowed cattle and a rich, loving family walked with him hand in hand, now a barren home and a diseased body oppresses his soul. The biblical figure, Job, with a truly faithful heart nonetheless remains pious and upright to his God. Despite his god-fearing nature though, poor, hapless Job, once an oriental chieftain whose name echoed throughout the East, cries out with such bleeding anguish for the ultimate reasoning behind his suffering. In the end, his story becomes the heroic sage of the human condition, turning tradegy into triumph because he disregarded things of this world.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>The Bible</Source>
<Quote>There the wicked cease from turmoil, and there the weary are at rest./Captives also enjoy their ease; they no longer hear the slave driver’s shout./The small and the great are there, and the slaves are freed from their owners./Why is light given to those in misery,and life to the bitter of soul,/to those who long for death that does not come, who search for it more than for hidden treasure,/who are filled with gladness and rejoice when they reach the grave?/Why is life given to a man whose way is hidden, whom God has hedged in?/For sighing has become my daily food; my groans pour out like water./What I feared has come upon me; what I dreaded has happened to me./I have no peace, no quietness; I have no rest, but only turmoil.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Job.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>57</ID>
<Character>John Coffey</Character>
<Description>The gentle giant who though innocent and by cruel circumstances was sentenced to death row for a crime he didn&apos;t commit; a sad, quiet reserved man always found weeping and being afraid of the dark. John Coffey of somewhat sub-average intelligence but superhuman size possesses the miraculous gift of healing. Sadly this calm, mild, innocent inmate dies on the electric chair but his humble yet hapless spirit roams beyond cell blocks and prison wards into the hearts and minds of feeling souls. Even if he is the lonely sparrow in the rain, he beckons all earth&apos;s inhabitants with all his childlike personality to be happy on a loving planet.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>The Green Mile, movie</Source>
<Quote>You tell God the Father it was a kindness you done. I know you hurtin&apos; and worryin&apos;, I can feel it on you, but you oughta quit on it now. Because I want it over and done. I do. I&apos;m tired, boss. Tired of bein&apos; on the road, lonely as a sparrow in the rain. Tired of not ever having me a buddy to be with, or tell me where we&apos;s coming from or going to, or why. Mostly I&apos;m tired of people being ugly to each other. I&apos;m tired of all the pain I feel and hear in the world everyday. There&apos;s too much of it. It&apos;s like pieces of glass in my head all the time.</Quote>
<LinkImage>JohnCoffey.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>58</ID>
<Character>Jurgis</Character>
<Description>A soul-torn Lithuanian immigrant whose American dream turned out to be a universal nightmare. With unrelenting toil in the meatpacking plants in Chicago, Jurgis must endure the merciless grind while working and the inhuman conditions while living in city slums. And Life in its continual torture forces the helpless, hopeless, hapless Jurgis to lose his house, his adoring wife, his infant son to unfortunate demises. And on through the city&apos;s brothels, bars, jails, and countrysides, Jurgis becomes another by-product of exploitation. </Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Jungle, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>Jurgis.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>59</ID>
<Character>Kattrin</Character>
<Description>The mute darling pushed along on a vending cart during the long, brutal Thirty Years&apos; War; the dumb daughter whose supple heart struggles on the dismal Europen landscape torn apart by Protestants and Catholics. Once by one poor Kattrin witnesses the absences of her brothers and the untimely calamities that only war can foster. She suffers from the virtues of kindness and pity with arms and a bosom aching to hold infant children. In a time where war paves the way for women&apos;s prostitution and rapings, Kattrin, the voiceless, ragged heroine, glimmers as a ray in the darkest of times. </Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>Mother Courage, play</Source>
<LinkImage>Kattrin.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>60</ID>
<Character>Laura Wingfield</Character>
<Description>The painfully shy darling, crippled with one leg slightly shorter than the other; the innocent, frail creature who withdraws from society and finds solace among glass animal figurines and an old phonograph. Poor Laura limited by her own self-consciousness sadly drops out of high school and business school. Now, the kind-faced, meek lady spends her time in an illusionarry world waiting for a gentleman caller to take her away. But eventually, the lame daughter and sister learns the beauty of imperfections; where all the world are duplicated horses, she is the unique unicorn; where all the world are weeds, she is blue roses.</Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>The Glass Menagerie, play</Source>
<Quote>I wish that you were my sister. I’d teach you to have some confidence in yourself. The different people are not like other people, but being different is nothing to be ashamed of. Because other people are not such wonderful people. They’re one hundred times one thousand. You’re one times one! They walk all over the earth. You just stay here. They’re common as—weeds, but—you—well, you’re—Blue Roses!</Quote>
<LinkImage>LauraWingfield.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>61</ID>
<Character>Lennie</Character>
<Description>A simple-minded, childlike migrant worker whose gentleness and kindness leads him to doom on the great American plains; a large, lumbering man quick to pet anything soft -small animals, dresses, hair- but was unaware of stone-hearted men when he petted the wrong object. Poor, innocent Lennie completely dependent on his weary partner dreams the peaceful, pleasant hope of a beautiful farm where he could tend at last to his beloved rabbits. Unaware of his own strength and his own heart, the mentally-challenged Lennie left prematurely from a world that didn&apos;t understand him and a world he didn&apos;t understand.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Of Mice and Men, novella</Source>
<LinkImage>Lennie.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>62</ID>
<Character>Lucynell Crater</Character>
<Description>The innocently pure darling used by the rogues of this world, misused by a weary Southern mother, then abused by a sad turn of events. Poor Lucynell, born deaf and mute, thought she found something to hope for but see it racing away toward the horizon. The sweet, gentle daughter who in the end was just a heavy burden to those closest to her. A rather large young woman close to thirty delighted just to learn how to pronounce &quot;bird.&quot; Yet, what reward comes to such meek beauty but a haphazard marriage and careless abandonment in a road side diner. Truly, this misunderstood, unknowing creature was an Angel of God for possessing human frailty in its rich, quiet essence.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>Flannery O&apos;Connor short story</Source>
<LinkImage>LucynellCrater.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>63</ID>
<Character>Maggie Fitzgerald</Character>
<Description>A trailer park hillbilly born into a life without hope somewhere between nowhere and goodbye; a thirty-one year old woman who grew up thinking she was trash, that she was nothing since a family emotionally disowned her. Eventually, the poor, low-paid waitress found her self-worth and dignity in a boxing ring, becoming an ersatz daughter to a stern, hard old man. Sadly poor Maggie suffers a tragic accident that hushed the many cheers and applause of a humble seed turned champion. But in the end, meek laughing soul Maggie lives up to her name &quot;chuisle&quot;, Gallic for &quot;darling.&quot;</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Million Dollar Baby, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>MaggieFitzgerald.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>64</ID>
<Character>Marilyn Cuberle</Character>
<Description>In a future world where uniformity and conformity are mandated principles, poor Marilyn Cuberle refuses to be assimilated in such a state. With a beautiful mind teeming with ideals of individuality, beauty, and the human spirit, the soul-torn Marilyn adamantly and blatantly declines an operation of generic beauty. But the eighteen-year old, inspired by a father who fought long and hard for his dignity, sadly loses the battle to convice an automaton world the worth of foreign thoughts and feelings. Yet even though her beliefs are now voiced from a collective conscience, a body now tucked underneath an assembly line figure, we still hear echoes of a rebel crying out.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Twilight Zone, tv show</Source>
<Quote>Have you ever read Shakespeare? Or Keats? Or Shelley? My father gave them to me and lots of others. Aristotle. Socrates. Dosteovsky. Did you know Dosteovsky was an epileptic? He was ugly. He was deformed. But he wrote about beauty, about real beauty. These men wrote about life, about the dignity of the individual, human spirit, and about love.</Quote>
<LinkImage>MarilynCuberle.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>65</ID>
<Character>Marshall Will Kane</Character>
<Description>A marshall of a town who embodies the very face of courage. When an outlaw fugitive with his band returns for revenge; when deputies are hard to enlist; when all the townspeople abandon him, Marshall Will Kane stands strong and ready to uphold justice even at the near cost of his life. Only a recent bride remains at his side, still keeping the promise of their wedding day. So on a Wild West showdown at high noon, a weary marshall and loyal wife exhibit core values of justice, devotion, courage, and love, more qualities than a tin star can represent.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>High Noon, movie</Source>
<Quote>Yeah, it&apos;s a good life! You risk your skin catching killers and the jury turns them loose so they can come back to shoot at you again. If you&apos;re honest, you pour your whole life. And in the end, you wind up dying all alone on some dirty street. For what? For nothing, for a tin star...It figures. It&apos;s all happens too sudden. People gotta talk themselves into law and order before they do anything about it. Maybe because deep down, they don&apos;t care. They just don&apos;t care.</Quote>
<LinkImage>MarshallKane.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>66</ID>
<Character>Mother in Black Christ</Character>
<Description>The old, aging relic, reticient, uncomplaining and ever so patient who endured a lifetime of woes but still holds steadfastly to her saving faith. Marred by anguished experiences, broken down by tribulating relationships, this poor mother still showers warmth and gentleness to a cold, bitter world. She knits by candlelight through weak eyes, threading with wrinkled hands, attached to frail limbs on a weary body frame. Gray hair and woe-ravaged eyes that tell of a crippled, soul-torn Negro story. And when a son is lynched and dies, this woman, Job&apos;s darker sister, embraces God with tremendous faith and patience. She proves that depsite the paucity of hopes, the scarcity of dreams, a lowly seed can have touches of divinity.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Countee Cullen poem, The Black Christ</Source>
<LinkImage>MotherBlackChrist.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>67</ID>
<Character>Mr. Freeze</Character>
<Description>Once a brilliant cryogenics researcher working to find a cure for his beloved wife, Nora, who became a callous, withdrawn willain bent on revenge. After a terrible accident that left him unable to survive out of a sub-zero environment, Mr. Freeze becomes a saddened, sensitive soul who would kill just to walk on a warm summer day with a hot wind in his face and a warm hand to hold. So the lonely, hapless man, whose only solace is a music box with his wife&apos;s memory, lives a cold, dead world alien to any human compassion or hope. </Description>
<SourceType>tv animated series</SourceType>
<Source>Batman, tv animated series</Source>
<Quote>Think of it Batman. To never again walk upon a summer&apos;s day with a hot wind in your face and a warm hand to hold. Oh yes, I&apos;d kill for that...I failed you. I wish there were another way for me to say it. I cannot. I can only beg your forgiveness and pray you hear me somehow... someplace. Someplace where a warm hand waits for mine.</Quote>
<LinkImage>MrFreeze.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>68</ID>
<Character>Mr. Smith</Character>
<Description>With an overnight rise in fame, a little known leader of boy rangers becomes a U.S. senator. Wet behind the ears. Mr. Smith tries to advance the people&apos;s business in the nation&apos;s capital. But his idealism, common goodness, is stopped dead in its tracks by the political machines, filibusters, the press, gridlock, and backroom power dealing. Mr. Smith learns betrayal for political manuevering; defacto events over hollow words of the founding fathers; money and power over love thy neighbor principles. But through the articles and amendments, Mr. Smith fights for a lost cause, embodying America&apos;s true promise.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Mr. Smith Goes to Washington, movie</Source>
<Quote>I guess this is just another lost cause, Mr. Paine. All you people don&apos;t know about lost causes. Mr. Paine does. He said once they were the only causes worth fighting for. And he fought for them once, for the only reason any man ever fights for them; because of just one plain simple rule: &apos;Love thy neighbor&apos;. And in this world today, full of hatred, a man who knows that one rule has a great trust. You know that rule, Mr. Paine, and I loved you for it, just as my father did.  And you know that you fight for the lost causes harder than for any other. Yes, you even die for them.</Quote>
<LinkImage>MrSmith.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>69</ID>
<Character>Mr. Spock</Character>
<Description>The quiet, resolute scientific-minded first officer who looks out on the world in logic terms. Half-Vulcan, half-human, Mr. Spock carries superior qualities yet a stable, understanding role. Through episodes of time portals, different dimensions, uncanny creatures, Mr. Spock stands true to a captain and crew. Lacking emotion, a starship is guided by a consistent hand. But an untold story of a distant homeland is harbored within him. All the knowledge and logic of the universe cannot hide his stifled hope to be free, impulsive, unpredictable, loving -to be human. </Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Star Trek: Original Series, tv show</Source>
<LinkImage>MrSpock.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>70</ID>
<Character>Mrs. Ramsay</Character>
<Description>The patient, sympathetic though-flowing woman on a summer trip to Isle of Skye. A mother who outpours defense and hope for her children; a wife who shoulders moral and social support for her agitated husband; a hostess bringing together the conflicting personalities to a dinner table. Though carrying conventional norms of gender roles, Mrs. Ramsay whimsically appreciates her family and guests. With an eye toward a lighthouse, toward a hopeful beam, this English woman coalesces experiences and personalities into the entangled tragic-comedic choatic collage called life.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>To the Lighthouse, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>MrsRamsay.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>71</ID>
<Character>Mulder</Character>
<Description>Bent on learning the truth of man and nature, the galaxy and stars, and government secrets, Mulder becomes entangled in the engulfing mystery. A passion born from losing a sister, the FBI agent chases at any cost the ultimate answer. In doing so, he loses both parents and almost loses his own life. But the hard-luck Mulder, who never quits, has a stable, scientifically-minded partner that keeps him sane and keeps him giong. Yet deep down in the mist of distrustful institutions and agendas, he carries a soul continually crying out: &quot;I want to believe.&quot;</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>X-Files, tv show</Source>
<Quote>I&apos;m the key figure in an ongoing government charade, the plot to conceal the truth about the existence of extraterrestrials. It&apos;s a global conspiracy, actually, with key players in the highest levels of power, that reaches down into the lives of every man, woman, and child on this planet, so, of course, no one believes me. I&apos;m an annoyance to my superiors, a joke to my peers. They call me Spooky. Spooky Mulder, whose sister was abducted by aliens when he was just a kid and who now chases after little green men with a badge and a gun, shouting to the heavens or to anyone who will listen that the fix is in, that the sky is falling and when it hits it&apos;s gonna be the shit-storm of all time.</Quote>
<LinkImage>FoxMulder.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>72</ID>
<Character>Musician, Weary Blues</Character>
<Description>The lone singer and musician who pours his moans into music. In a small corner of a Harlem nightclub, a sad soul plays a piano melody and sings woeful lyrics to any listening ear. We don&apos;t know his name, but we feel his pain. We don&apos;t know his story but we connect with its themes of weariness, unhappiness, and loneliness; the same life themes that springs from lost loves, failed jobs, abandoned cots, monotonous hours, empty pockets, starved hopes...And yet instead of wallowing in self-pity, art is produced, music is played. And we accept this as a lasting artifact of the human condition.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Langston Hughes poem, The Weary Blues</Source>
<LinkImage>MusicianWearyBlues.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>73</ID>
<Character>Newman</Character>
<Description>The archenemy neighbor who after the conniving, plotting, scheming is just an ordinary, lonely tenant of the city. A laughable, eccentric postal worker who like all people dreams simple dreams like an easy, long-sought mail route and affectionate love returned. Newman mixes poetry with comedy and deep underneath we hear the groan of a simple, working class everyman trying to make it in life&apos;s hustle and bustle. He doesn&apos;t surmount the institution. He doesn&apos;t beat the odds. He doesn&apos;t win the girl but the audience still root for him and cheer him on all the way.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Seinfeld, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>And therein lies the tragedy. For I believe, sadly for you, that there is but one woman meant for each of us. One perfect angel for whom we are put on this earth. One winsome tulip we ceaselessly yearn for throughout our dreary, workaday lives! And you, my friend, have found your angel. I can tell. For my heart has also been captured by a breathless beauty - whom I fear I will never possess.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Newman.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>74</ID>
<Character>Obscure Youth</Character>
<Description>Just a namless youth dreaming upon a cloud who learns the weighty truth of the universe, that all things and efforts are vain. A looming voice over head casts a shadow on the youth&apos;s dreams. All his hopes for fame and fortune, respect and reverence, awe and acknowledgement are dashed down. Where he dreams crowds to cheer him, only empty fields will welcome him. Where he thought Glory would caress, only Failure will scar him. We rise with his innocent passion and sink with his gloomy realization. And so the obscure youth continues on his way -lost and lonely- towards an unmarked grave.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Walt Whitman poem, Ambition</Source>
<LinkImage>ObscureYouth.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>75</ID>
<Character>Perth</Character>
<Description>The nearly sixty-year old crewmember aboard the fateful Pequod who once lived a blithe family life with a doting wife and three loving children. However, after a desperate burglary rampaged his home, a lost battle with alcoholism; and wife and kids meeting their untimley ends. poor, pitiful Perth stood alone in all the world. He had no home, no family, no heart, just an anvil and iron at hand. So when Death failed to knock on his door even when he longed for it, he found refuge on the high seas. There, the hapless old man pounded away with a hardened hammer and saddened soul.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Moby Dick, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>Perth.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>76</ID>
<Character>Quasimodo</Character>
<Description>The deformed, deaf bell ringer of Notre Dame who carries within him the purest of hearts, the noblest of souls. Unloved at birth, shunned in life, the lonely hunchback thought to be a monster by the public, hides from the world in dark crevices and corners. Yet the unattached, &quot;almost human&quot; creature willingly fights for good and against evil. Even amid a tragic story of unrequited love, Quasimodo loves to the end. From public disdain to private triumph, the monstrous outer hide of this Parisian bell ringer sheds off to a beautiful, meek interior soul.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Hunchback of Notre Dame, novel</Source>
<LinkImage>Quasimodo.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>77</ID>
<Character>Waiting Man</Character>
<Description>The hopeful young man who waits eagerly for his love amidst the closing of a church ceremony. But the waiting drags on and on an on, and still on. With painstaking patience and stamina, he sits and hopes. But hope dims like the candlelight nearby. The awful refrain chimes through his sad, crushed soul: &quot;she will not come, the woman that he waits.&quot; He saw the hair, the eyes, and felt the touch, the kiss, but all were fading dreams. Head bowed, tears forming, his innocence is lost. Love that sprouted with brimming hope is dashed down to an abandoned nail laid bare.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Alan Seeger poem, Rendezvous</Source>
<Quote>Fond, fervent heart of life&apos;s enamored spring,/So true, so confident, so passing fair,/That thought of Love as some sweet, tender thing,/And not as war, red tooth and nail laid bare,/How in that hour its innocence was slain,/How from that hour our disillusion dates,/When first we learned thy sense, ironical refrain,/She will not come, the woman that he waits.</Quote>
<LinkImage>WaitingMan.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>78</ID>
<Character>Robert Barone</Character>
<Description>The gargantuan police lieutenant who is reduced in size by a successful younger brother, stifling parents, and untimely romantic encounters. An honest, loving gentle giant oftentimes slighted by a mother, and shadowed by a brother. Forever with a frown on his face, poor Robert swelters through a difficult, inconvenienced life. Yet however the winds blow at hims, snows pile on him, or the sun scorches him, hapless Robert still serves as an affectionate virtuous family member be it a brother, son, or uncle. The neglected leviathan who manages to dance his blues away, showing us all that it&apos;s not the circumstances that make the meek but the response to it. </Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Everybody Loves Raymond, sitcom</Source>
<LinkImage>RobertBarone.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>79</ID>
<Character>Rogue</Character>
<Description>The soul-torn darling blessed with a sensitive spirit and cursed with a mutant body; a beautiful brunette having touches of gray locks who fights long and hard for noble values and ideals as a member of the X-Men. But in between battles, poor, hapless Rogue wanders astray limited by her own powerful prowess. Having the keen ability to involuntarily absorb any being&apos;s memories and physical strength simply by a touch, the southern belle&apos;s innocent hopes of fond embraces and tender kisses are sadly dashed down. So from a disowned family to unsuccessful romantic liaisons, Rogue agonizes through the years, ready to give up her all-powerful abilities just for a human touch. </Description>
<SourceType>tv animated series</SourceType>
<Source>X-Men, tv animated series</Source>
<LinkImage>Rogue.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>80</ID>
<Character>Roz Doyle</Character>
<Description>The hard-luck radio show producer struggling in the usual twentieth century quandaries: juggling a career and a love life, all while being a single mother. Despite sinking in the quicksands of a sexual-young-money-job world, poor Roz fights such social forces with the love of an infant daughter and sincere co-workers and friends. But still, the average joe 38-year old heroine feels incomplete as if a gaping hole cratered itself within her condo apartment, SUV, checkbook hassel of an existence; the searches for Mr. Right that always end up wrong. But no tragedy do we see unfold in this candid, soul-torn darling but an example that even a hard-working mother will have her deserving place in the sun.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Frasier, sitcom</Source>
<Quote>Forty-seven? I have a suggestion for you, Stu. Grow the hell up! I&apos;m thirty-eight. And I FEEL thirty-eight. Now, I know we&apos;re all supposed to act like perpetual teenagers these days, but you know what? I like acting my age. I like being a mom. I like having a career. And I like balancing my checkbook! When did it become such a bad thing to be an adult?! Now, don&apos;t get me wrong, I had a great time when I was younger, I did! But after a while, that way of life just seems empty. You have to go deeper, and commit to things that really matter to you. Believe me, when you do that, you&apos;ll find out how amazing and rich life can be.</Quote>
<LinkImage>RozDoyle.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>81</ID>
<Character>Ruth Younger</Character>
<Description>The Chicagoan housewife, weary and tired, through the years. As finances dissolve, a marriage is strained. Ruth tries to keep keeping on but all seems hard and long. Yet she refuses self-pity or being the outlet for an estranged husband to vent. Ruth holds the house together and finds underneath the misery and despair the core family values of love and devotion. The worn-out mother and wife, carrying the piled centuries of black woman&apos;s strength, learns that struggle and strife make way for character and integrity. Even with a growing seed in her, another pile on the burden, Ruth is ready to nurture and cultivate.</Description>
<SourceType>play</SourceType>
<Source>A Raisin in the Sun, play</Source>
<LinkImage>RuthYounger.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>82</ID>
<Character>Santiago</Character>
<Description>An old man with a feud on the water off a Cuban coast. For eighty-four, tiresome days Santiago casts his line out with no bite as a nearby town mocks him. His waiting and hoping mirrors the same among humanity from Adam down. Then suddenly, he violently  tugs and pulls at a large marlin. So the man versus nature battle plays out. Suffering with hubris and tantalizing hope, Santiago succombs to defeat as sharks devour his catch. With the defeat, we feel for the old man on the usual trajectory of meek stories: hoping, waiting, loving, waiting, then losing and dying.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>The Old Man and the Sea, novella</Source>
<LinkImage>Santiago.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>83</ID>
<Character>Seven of Nine</Character>
<Description>Once part of the collective mind known as the Borg then forced out into the automaton assimilation of alien races, now the soul-torn beign continuously fighting for her humanity. Rather then the unfeeling existence of a Borg drone, Seven of Nine attempts to find her individuality through many ups and downs. During such a turbulent journey, the beautiful space woman learns a little about human nature adn the great hope of being unique. So thought after thought, feeling after feeling, Seven of Nine&apos;s robotic coat of arms are exchanged for living flesh and a consious mind without resistance. She gladly takes some chaos instead of following the all-powerful, stagnant, stifling order. </Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Star Trek: Voyager, tv show</Source>
<LinkImage>SevenofNine.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>84</ID>
<Character>Silver Surfer</Character>
<Description>The noble herald of an all-powerful planet devourer who exhibits compassion to its highest. Once a restless citizen of a utopian world, Silver Surfer gave up his freedom and sacrificed himself for a planet to become a sentinel of the spaceways. After personally witnessing the breathtaking beauties of Earth, the sensitive Silver Surfer rebels against his master in roaming the cosmos for planets to feed on. His rebellion sentences him to prison within Earth. Thus, this tragic, soul-torn, sentient being proves to be a benevolent alien; a contemplative philosopher; a gentle poet; an astute journalist, pure in heart and true in spirit, who shows us how Earth truly is a Garden of Eden.</Description>
<SourceType>tv animated series</SourceType>
<Source>Fantastic Four, tv animated series</Source>
<LinkImage>SilverSurfer.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>85</ID>
<Character>Soap Opera Girl</Character>
<Description>A subway terminal passenger who only wanted a more human world; a sensitive, simple stranger tired of society&apos;s hustling and bustling, scurrying and hurrying through life. This unnamed darling who wanted every poet&apos;s heartrending hope to come true: to slow down the pace, smell the flowers, connect with friends and strangers, soak the atmosphere, loiter in the sun, harken to people&apos;s hearts, cherish human moments. But we know all too well the polite, efficient, robotic life we manuever through. Yet a beautiful tender young lady, able to stop one&apos;s rushing ways, opens to us the lost beauty of simply surviving day to day.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Waking Life, movie</Source>
<Quote>Hey. Could we do that again? I know we haven&apos;t met, but I don&apos;t want to be an ant. You know? I mean, it&apos;s like we go through life with our antennas bouncing off one another, continously on ant autopilot, with nothing really human required of us. Stop. Go. Walk here. Drive there. All action basically for survival. All communication simply to keep this ant colony buzzing along in an efficient, polite manner. &quot;Here&apos;s your change.&quot; &quot;Paper or plastic?&apos; &quot;Credit or debit?&quot; &quot;You want ketchup with that?&quot; I don&apos;t want a straw. I want real human moments. I want to see you. I want you to see me. I don&apos;t want to give that up. I don&apos;t want to be ant, you know?</Quote>
<LinkImage>SoapOperaGirl.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>86</ID>
<Character>Soldier Boy</Character>
<Description>A sad, innocent kid who instead of receiving a female peer&apos;s fond embrace or male friend&apos;s extended hand, was given a bayonet, some grenades, and all the lonely bunkers and trenches to waste away childhood idealism. His entire service in the armed forces was the unyielding routine and regiment, destruction and death. The poor, hapless soldier lad, who paraded in violent platoons and infantries, an infant himself, sadly endures mornings that melt into evenings with meal breaks of rum and despair. Then, when we hear of his voluntary, premature death we are quick to castigate hims rather than the horrible invention of mankind, war, that forced him to it. </Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Siegfried Sassoon poem</Source>
<LinkImage>SoldierBoy.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>87</ID>
<Character>Speaker, A Winter Piece</Character>
<Description>The agitated poet caught in the cares of life finds refuge in the tranquil ambience of a winter scene. Among dead tree limbs and the dearth of vegatation, the speaker feels one with nature&apos;s spoils. Rained down by the ills of existence, the lonely poet finds companionship adn belonging in the barren woods. We feel his pain melt away. He soon forgets his strife and becomes engulfed in the merry hum of bee, the feathery snow, the fountain&apos;s brink, the fresh, sylvan air, the fringe of summer flowers, the rain that glazed the snow, the massy trunks cased in pure crystal...</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>William Cullen Bryant poem, A Winter Piece</Source>
<Quote>The time has been that these wild solitudes,/Yet beautiful as wild, were trod by me/Oftener than now; and when the ills of life/Had chafed my spirit--when the unsteady pulse/Beat with strange flutterings--I would wander forth/And seek the woods. The sunshine on my path/Was to me as a friend. The swelling hills,/The quiet dells retiring far between,/With gentle invitation to explore/Their windings, were a calm society/That talked with me and soothed me. Then the chant/Of birds, and chime of brooks, and soft caress/Of the fresh sylvan air, made me forget/The thoughts that broke my peace, and I began/To gather simples by the fountain&apos;s brink,/And lose myself in day-dreams.</Quote>
<LinkImage>SpeakerWinterPiece.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>88</ID>
<Character>Speaker, The Suicide</Character>
<Description>A sensitive dame, heart-bleeding and soul-wrenching, from her arch nemesis, Life. Starved and mocked, emotionally battered and bruised, this unnamed narrator yearns for peace and freedom. With all dreams dissolved, all songs quieted, she cries out with all she ever wanted: a childhood home and playing freely in the sun. Lament after lament, she finally escapes out through a certain door. To her great joy and hope, once crushed to dust in life, she finds her house on a hill, a loving father, songs never to be hushed, and a sun always to be enjoyed.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Edna St. Vincent Millay poem, The Suicide</Source>
<LinkImage>SpeakerTheSuicide.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>89</ID>
<Character>Spiderman</Character>
<Description>The friendly, neighborhood hero who wall crawls and swings off buildings on behalf of New York City. Yet underneath the mask and costume is the scientific-minded Peter Parker filled with insecurities and inadequacies. A nerd who never rose stellar on the job or won the girl is nonetheless the witty Spiderman saving the city of goblins and kingpins. Constantly challenged and tested beyond superhuman endurance, shunned at times by a city, losing loves and friends in an entangled web of mutants and crime, Spiderman fights for the little things: a sick girl, a dedicated co-worker, a lost uncle.</Description>
<SourceType>tv animated series</SourceType>
<Source>Spiderman, tv animated series</Source>
<LinkImage>Spiderman.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>90</ID>
<Character>Steve Urkel</Character>
<Description>America&apos;s well-known nerd who stood up for the millions of highly intelligent pupils with social awkardness. Clad in red suspenders, high-water pants, and thick-rimmed glasses, Steve Urkel has turned the looked down upon geek into a dignified hero. Nonetheless, poor Steve finds himself always stumbling into accidents, mumbling to girls and peers. He suffers frequent ridicules, taunts, and self-inadequacies but his meek, lowly spirit holds a mirror up to human nature, helping to show the narcissitic, egotistic mankind the error of its shallow ways.</Description>
<SourceType>tv show</SourceType>
<Source>Family Matters, sitcom</Source>
<LinkImage>SteveUrkel.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>91</ID>
<Character>The Terminator</Character>
<Description>Once a determined machine bent on destruction and death, now a learning machine here to serve and protect. From a world of darkness and war, the Terminator must return to a past to save a future. In the gruesome combat against an impossible foe, the Terminator fights to its death, sacrificing himself in the end. Yet he learns along the way the human ways of loyalty, sympathy, and friendship. More than knowledge banks and memory chips in a local mainframe, a soul is present. Who knew robots, machines, could mirror human nature? Who knew a terminator could cherish the value of life?</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Terminator 2, movie</Source>
<Quote>The unknown future rolls toward us. I face it, for the first time, with a sense of hope. Because if a machine, a Terminator, can learn the value of human life, maybe we can too.</Quote>
<LinkImage>TheTerminator.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>92</ID>
<Character>The Thing</Character>
<Description>The rock-skin creature of enormous power and strength yet carries a heart bleeding of self-pity. From a radioactive space accident, the Thing formerly Ben Gordon, a normal looking human being has become a pithy, down-to-earth, monstrous crime-stopper. Among a quartet of superheros, the Thing has found his place. But after the clobberin&apos; time, the galaxy wars, the super villains, he feels ugly and ashamed of his appearance. Even with a blind girlfriend who sees his beautiful, noble soul, the Thing feels inadequate. And when told &apos;beauty lies within&apos;, he nods, sighs, and shrugs his shoulders in silence as he walks away.</Description>
<SourceType>tv animated series</SourceType>
<Source>Fantastic Four, tv animated series</Source>
<LinkImage>TheThing.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>93</ID>
<Character>The Tramp</Character>
<Description>The always romantic vagabond who turned life&apos;s black and white silent show into a rich, colorful golden symphony. Hard-luck by the stringent economic insecurities of the times, this playful little tramp always makes the most of his poor, downtrodden existence. Always a girl&apos;s affections to win and a normal life to muster, the lovable tramp frolics and dances into the hearts of many generations. Ultimately, the tramp reminds us all of the unique beauty, long-lasting and worthwhile, that can be found in the dirtiest of slums, the most ragged of people, and the worst conditions of lfie.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Charlie Chaplin silent movies</Source>
<LinkImage>TheTramp.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>94</ID>
<Character>Thereza Ambrose</Character>
<Description>The suicidal, young ballerina saved at the last minute. Sunken with the despair of all aimless life and unfortunate family, Thereza is paralyzed in body and mind. But a friend, a stranger, a neighbor, lifts her up and recaptures her desire for life. She slowly gains her walking ability and then the grace of her dancing ability. Through it all she pours out a sad gentleness and re-awakened aura born out of friendship and human care. The spotlight and limelight of show business pales to her spirit. The cheers and applause are hushed to the music of her love. So we watch as she twirls, spins, and sways into our rigid, lackluster hearts.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Limelight, movie</Source>
<LinkImage>TherezaAmbrose.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>95</ID>
<Character>Tiny Tim</Character>
<Description>The sweet, lovable young boy wrought in the deprivation of England&apos;s poor. Despite being crippled at birth, Tiny Tim has not proven crippled in heart. With a mild temperament infused with a gentle humor and a benevolent spirit, a sparkling gem grew in the dirty, cold repugnance of urban poverty. A crutch at hand, a loving nature in soul, Tiny Tim has been welcomed by all even ruthless and callous men. He has indeed the child essence of God who sought inexpensive joy with his family and reminds all people who made lame beggars walk and blind men see.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>A Christmas Carol, novella</Source>
<Quote>He told me, coming home, that he hoped the people saw him in the church, because he was a cripple, and it might be pleasant to them to remember upon Christmas Day, who made lame beggars walk, and blind men see.</Quote>
<LinkImage>TinyTim.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>96</ID>
<Character>Tod Clifton</Character>
<Description>The clean-dressed, eloquent, handsome African American leader of a revolutionary cause who is gunned down by the police on a street on a hot summer day. Part of a Brotherhood to organize a movement and disenfranchised people, Tod Clifton fought hard street corner after street corner until his death. He met his match though on one street corner where Sambo dolls were sold. A policeman with an eager finger put the Harlem youth leader in his place. Tod was an idealistic hope that died young, a hero of a lost cause, a human who died like a dog in a road.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>Invisible Man, novel</Source>
<Quote>Think of your own brother or your cousin John. His lips were thick with an upward curve at the corners. He often smiled. He had good eyes and a pair of fair hands, and he had a heart. He thought about things and he felt deeply. I won’t call him noble because what’s such a word to do with one of us? His name was Clifton, Tod Clifton, and, like any man, he was born of woman to live awhile and fall and die. So that’s his tale to the minute. His name was Clifton and for a while he lived among us and aroused a few hopes in the young manhood of man, and we who knew him loved him and he died...His name was Clifton, Tod Clifton, he was unarmed and his death was as senseless as his life was futile. He had struggled for Brotherhood on a hundred street corners and he thought it would make him more human, but he died like any dog in a road.</Quote>
<LinkImage>TodClifton.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>97</ID>
<Character>Tommy Wilhelm</Character>
<Description>The agitated, middle-aged man who finds himself alienated and on the brink of total failure. Separated from his wife and sons, distanced from a father, Tommy will refute the poet&apos;s line -&quot;no man is an island complete unto himself.&quot; From an actor to salesman with odd jobs in between, Tommy holds up a disappointing resume of life. And on a Day of Reckoning, he tries desperately with a cold father and shot at the stock market. Thoughts and emotions crowd in him as New York pounds down on him. In the distance is a funeral that carries a message to the iconic middle-class, frustrated man caught on hard times.</Description>
<SourceType>story</SourceType>
<Source>Saul Bellow short story</Source>
<LinkImage>TommyWilhelm.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>98</ID>
<Character>Trip</Character>
<Description>A defiant, hateful runaway slave who eventually becomes one of the bravest heroes of the 54th Massachusetts Regiment during the Civil War. Torn into bits and pieces of rage and revenge due to blatant racism, countless lashes from the whip, and ruthless chases by hounds, Trip epitomizes the dispossessed soldier of the Union army. Yet despite the anguish poverty, the Negro ex-slave becomes a noteworthy fighter and learns the everlasting beauty of family and friends and camaraderie. Though he won himself a grave, Trip won the chance to fight against humanity&apos;s cruelest system, slavery.</Description>
<SourceType>movie</SourceType>
<Source>Glory, movie</Source>
<Quote>I ain&apos;t much about no prayin&apos;, now. I ain&apos;t never had no family, and... killed off my mama. Well, I just... Y&apos;all&apos;s the onliest family I got. I love the 54th. Ain&apos;t even much a matter what happens tomorrow, &apos;cause we men, ain&apos;t we?</Quote>
<LinkImage>Trip.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>99</ID>
<Character>Weary Slave, Banjo Song</Character>
<Description>The weary slave who after a long, ardous day finds peace and solace with a banjo and singing family. An old-fashioned man who would gladly exchange heaven&apos;s harps with a country banjo. With a wife, children, and gray-haired granny to sing alongside, we see sorrow, daily cares, aches, pains, troubles, disappear into song and laughter. The whole human saga of pain and joy rings in his heart. The black and white world is colored with tunes. Not minding the poor and rough sound, we learn the breadth and purpose of music; the love of family; the powerful testimony of the poor and meek.</Description>
<SourceType>poem</SourceType>
<Source>Paul Laurence Dunbar poem, A Banjo Song</Source>
<LinkImage>WearySlave.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
<Characters>
<ID>100</ID>
<Character>Winston</Character>
<Description>Caught in an overly scrutinized, dystopic London, Winston moves robotically through the eyes of Big Brother and chase of the Thought Police. Any thought veering out of the groupthink, citizens are apprehended and vaporized. But Winston becomes an unknowing rebel who keeps a personal journal and illicit photograph. Slowly he even melts away his robotic nature for a human soul moved by one innocent note long thought to be alien words -&quot;I love you.&quot; Of course, the rebel loses, beaten and tortured to death but an inkling of human consciousness remains.</Description>
<SourceType>novel</SourceType>
<Source>1984, novel</Source>
<Quote>For some reason Winston suddenly found himself thinking of Mrs Parsons, with her wispy hair and the dust in the creases of her face. Within two years those children would be denouncing her to the Thought Police. Mrs Parsons would be vaporized. Syme would be vaporized. Winston would be vaporized. O’Brien would be vaporized. Parsons, on the other hand, would never be vaporized. The eyeless creature with the quacking voice would never be vaporized. The little beetle-like men who scuttle so nimbly through the labyrinthine corridors of Ministries they, too, would never be vaporized. And the girl with dark hair, the girl from the Fiction Department — she would never be vaporized either. It seemed to him that he knew instinctively who would survive and who would perish: though just what it was that made for survival, it was not easy to say.</Quote>
<LinkImage>Winston.jpg</LinkImage>
</Characters>
</dataroot>
